# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave — Miami Beach, FL 33140

☎ (305) 894-6475 • ☒ aaron@niskin.org • ੴ aaron.niskin.org

HR Department October 3, 2016

Blackrock 40 East 52nd Street 10022 New York, NY

Dear Sir or Madam,

When my professor, Dr. Gary Kalmanovich, told me about Jacopo, a bit about his research, and the internship possibility at Blackrock, my interest was piqued. Some people find satisfaction in learning a thing and sticking with it. I am not one of those people. I prefer to live on the edge of my own understanding, constantly venturing further into the unknown. This outlook has resulted in my taking nearly every Math course my alma mater had to offer, and my desire to enter the field of Finance (the undisputed king of the unknown). This preference is not solely a personally beneficial stance, but rather has lead to many workplace improvements.

As an example, I recall one instance from my Army days. For several missions, we would perform our standard communications checks without any issues, but later on we would find ourselves unable to communicate. Our Commo Sergeant said this was an unavoidable phenomena, which didn't sound reasonable to me. I (a Private at the time) conducted my own investigation. To put a long story short, it turns out that these radios have to be synced in order to communicate (a cryptographic necessity), and every time portions of the unit were separated for a few minutes by a land barrier they would fall out of sync. I discovered that this, being a known problem, has a solution and I re-engineered our company radios so that we never had that problem again.

I believe my penchant for learning, problem solving, and optimizing things would make me a valuable member of the team at Blackrock. I realize that to say this will be a challenge would be putting it lightly, but that fact only serves to motivate me further. I am looking forward to many late nights with textbooks and my computer, finding ways to optimize code, etc.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration. If you have any questions and or comments, please feel free to contact me at any time.

Sincerely yours,

#### Aaron Niskin

Attached: Resumé

# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave - Miami Beach, FL 33140

☎ (305) 894-6475 • ⊠ aaron@niskin.org • ७ aaron.niskin.org

## **Skills and Languages**

**Advanced**: Spanish | JAVASCRIPT, HTML, PYTHON\*, R\*

Intermediate: Hebrew | CLOJURE, SCHEME, HOPLON, CSS, MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, NODEJS

Basic: German | JAVA, HASKELL, MONGODB, LATEX, MATLAB, OCTAVE

\*Projected - based on current workload

## **Education**

New College of Florida

Master's In Data Science

2016–(2018)

### Florida International University

Miami

Bachelor of Science | Mathematics | Minors | Physics and English

2012-2015

- Graduated Cum Laude GPA 3.64 (3.79 in major)
- Dean's List (6 times)

Miami Dade College
Associate of Arts
2010–2011

- Graduated with Honors GPA 3.74 out of 4.00
- Dean's List (5 times)
- Physics Award

## **Experience**

Florida Vocation Institute

Miami

Computer Science Instructor

2015-2016

- Taught and created syllabi for courses in HTML, CSS, CSS-Frameworks, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Functional-Programming, and Basic-Logic
- Created a free online course intended to teach aspiring students about the above subjects through interesting projects (currently live at www.fvi-grad.com)

### Math-Busters (www.Math-Busters.com)

Miami

Co-founder and Math/Science/Computing Tutor

2010-2015

- Tutored all levels of students from Elementary School to upper-level University students
- Maintained a perfect five-star rating on Wyzant.com (with over 100 ratings and over 450 hours logged)

#### Military

## 1-38 Infantry Regiment, 4/2 ID, US Army

Fort Lewis, WA

Infantryman

2006-2009

- Deployed to Iraq for OIF V from 2007-2008
- Held Team Leader, Rifleman, M-240B Machine Gunner, M-249 SAW gunner, RTO, Grenadier, and Marksman positions
- Combat Lifesaver certification
- Fought forest fires in Winthrop, Washington.

## 478th Civilian Affairs Battalion, US Army

Perrine, FL

Civil Affairs Specialist

2004-2006

- Trained at the John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center and School in Fort Bragg, NC for 6 months.
- Obtained Secret Clearance